Sofia Papadopoulou

Email: papadopoulou sof@hotmail.com Address: Apartment 13, 8 Greek Street **Mobile:** (+44)7523754905, (+30)6977931376 Park Row Apartments, LS1 5RW, Leeds, UK

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/sofia-papadopoulou-a130915a/

Game Programmer at Red Kite Games Ltd. Actively working in game development and porting AAA titles in consoles and streaming platforms. Programmer with 3.5 years of experience in ASP.NET and SQL administration. Approximately 5 years of experience in web development.

Software C++, C#, Unity, Unity Cloud, Unreal Engine, Microsoft Visual Studio, Perforce, Experience ASP.NET Framework, SQL, BizTalk Server, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React

GitHub: https://github.com/sopa92

Experience

Work Game Programmer, Red Kite Games Ltd, UK

- Game Development (C++) practicing Agile Methodologies
- Porting Games in Next Gen Streaming Platform and Consoles

Unity Developer, Nosebleed Interactive Ltd, UK

Apr 2020 – Aug 2020, Work Placement

- Game Development (Unity, C#) practicing Agile Methodologies
- Gameplay Design and Implementation

Programmer, Plaisio Computers S.A, Greece

Nov 2015 – Jun 2019

Sep 2020 - Present

- Software Development (ASP.NET, C#) practicing Agile Methodologies
- Application & Database Server Administration
- Monitoring, Maintenance and Upgrading (www.plaisio.gr, www.plaisiopro.gr)
- Communication Development and Monitoring between Web-Applications and SAP
- Research for upcoming technology trends and new e-commerce solutions
- Research for optimization, performance, scalability and reliability of Web Applications

Web Developer, Aboutnet, Greece

Jul 2014 – Jul 2015, 2 months internship included

- Responsive websites' Development (Joomla and OpenCart)
- Tutoring customers-clients on their websites' administration
- Database administration and Research on Seblod kit

Web Content Administrator, European Association on Signal Processing, Greece

Mar 2014 - May 2016

Website content update & Redesign on www.eurasip.org

Education

MSc in Computer Game Engineering, Newcastle University, UK

Sep 2019 - Sep 2020

 Related courses: Advanced Programming for Games in C++, Advanced Graphics for Games, Advanced Game Technologies, Game Technology Innovations, Engineering Gaming Solutions within a Team

BSc in Information Technology, University of Piraeus, Greece

Sep 2010 - Mar 2016

- Major: Software Engineering and Intelligent Systems Final Grade: 7.46/10, Very Good
- Thesis: "Educational Software for Dance Learning in Virtual Environment" (Unity3D development, motion capturing via Xbox360 Kinect, animation processing/exporting)
- Related courses: Human-Computer Interaction, Artificial Intelligence and Expert Systems, Computer Graphics, Multimedia Systems, Virtual Reality, Software Engineering

Online Courses • & Seminars •

- "Unreal Engine 4: How to Develop Your First Two Games" (Udemy) Feb 2018
- "The Ultimate Guide to Game Development with Unity (2018.2.x)" (Udemy) Nov 2018
- "Designing Game Puzzles in Unity" (Pluralsight) May 2017
- "Creating UI Elements for Games in Unity" (Pluralsight) Jul 2017
- Seminar with subject: "Introduction to Game Design, Game Development and Kinect", presented by: StudentsGuru Unipi - Jun 2014
- Seminar with subject: "Unity Development on Windows 8 GameAthlon", presented by: Carl Callewaert (Lead Technical Evangelist in Unity) & Jaime Rodriguez (Principal Program Manager in Microsoft Corporation) - Jun 2014

Languages & Certificates

Languages

- Greek: Native
- English: IELTS, British Council, C1 Sep 2018
- English: Certificate of Proficiency in English, University of Michigan, C2 May 2011
- French: DELF B2 Jan 2007

Other Certificates

Certified Sitecore Professional Developer - Mar 2018

Volunteer • Experience

- Member of "Plai Sou": Corporate Social Responsibility team of Plaisio Computers
- Foster Parent in Actionaid
- Foster Parent in WWF

Honors Plaisio Dream Team: Award for semester's best employees of Plaisio Computers - Oct 2018

Interests Travelling, Gaming, Cross training, Escape Rooms, Puzzles and Riddles, Dancing